<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>travel on nrd blog</title>
    <link>/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in travel on nrd blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nathanrdodson&#34;&gt;Nathan Dodson&lt;/a&gt; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 17:32:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Granada, España - Day 1</title>
      <link>/posts/granada-day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 17:32:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/granada-day1/</guid>
      <description>After a long day the night before, my mom and I weren’t particularly quick to get out of bed. We dragged ourselves downstairs by 10:30am before the breakfast closed at 11. The breakfast was what you would expect from a standard European hotel - lots of cheeses and cold meats, alongside juice and pastries.
We had originally planned for this day to be a quiet day to familiarize ourself with the city, and that is almost exactly what it ended up being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landed in Spain</title>
      <link>/posts/granada-day0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 11:32:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/granada-day0/</guid>
      <description>The next step in our European adventure takes place in the lovely city of Granada, Spain. Our flight from Manchester was only a short 2.5 hours, and customs in Granada was a breeze (the customs agent was super cool, he gave me a stamp). Getting off the plane, we were met with the beautiful Granada sun, pictured below in all of its glory:
Our driver was prompt, and spoke little English which was to be expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Few Days in the UK</title>
      <link>/posts/unitedkingdomtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 11:32:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/unitedkingdomtime/</guid>
      <description>Arriving in the Manchester International Airport was less stressful than I initially anticipated it to be - we got through customs without even talking to anyone, got our bags within the next 10 minutes, and met up with my Aunt. In terms of sleepiness, the excitement of meeting everyone overcame that feeling for the first few hours. When we landed, mind you, it was 7:30am so I had a whole day to get through (after having got no sleep on the plane…).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the air!</title>
      <link>/posts/intheair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 11:32:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/intheair/</guid>
      <description>So my really well thought out plan to beat the jet lag failed miserably. It was about 9:00pm CST, and I decided that with five hours left in the flight I should just try and go to sleep then and there, Well I got my headphones plugged in and music turned on and sleep mask ready - I was asleep in 10 minutes,,,, Only to wake up 30 minutes later, unable to sleep any longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip Preparation</title>
      <link>/posts/tripprep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 11:32:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tripprep/</guid>
      <description>For my trip to Europe, my preparation has been significantly more intensive than what would be considered “normal” on previous trips I’ve had. This is mainly because I have set a few goals for myself, some small, and some much larger.
For starters, I want to beat the jet lag - at least on my flight to Manchester. Our current itinerary has us leaving Atlanta at 6:00PM and arriving in Manchester just before 7:00AM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>/posts/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 10:32:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>So in just over four days I am heading to Europe for an incredible trip with my mom. It is something that I have been looking forward to for a while, and is definitely a place that is conducive to taking lots and lots of photos. I am looking to also try out my new GoPro Hero 7 Black while I’m there and throughout the trip in general as well - we shall see how that goes…</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>