<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>travel on nrd-blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in travel on nrd-blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© Nathan Dodson 2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 11:15:13 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://blog.nathandodson.com/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Atalaya Upper Mountain Trail</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/newmexico-2021/newmexico2021-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 11:15:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/newmexico-2021/newmexico2021-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-6-20.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Atalaya Mountain Trail&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Me at the trailhead.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved this trail for a couple of reasons; namely, the trailhead was in the middle of a high-end development, and it was funny to see all these fancy homes with an actual mountain just hanging out in their backyard. The hike itself was moderately challenging, and the weather could have been better but we made the most of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-6-15.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Initial Views&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rolling mountain range was picturesque for most of our hike, and it didn&amp;rsquo;t take long before all of Santa Fe came into view. This trail in particular was 6.2 miles out-and-back with an 1,800 foot elevation gain, although the range has hundreds of miles of trails with varied difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-6-04.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;At the Top&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Getting to the top was a real treat - stunning views for a trail that was 10 minutes from our place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that evening, we went to Meow Wolf after some recommendations from various people which was an enjoyable change of pace before finishing off the day - our last full day - at our favorite Tune Up Café. Thank you for the great trip New Mexico!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Georgia O&#39;Keefe&#39;s Ghost Ranch</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/newmexico-2021/newmexico2021-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 10:39:35 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/newmexico-2021/newmexico2021-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-5-34.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Entering the ranch&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was a last-minute change of plans to explore the beautiful Ghost Ranch, home to the late Georgia O&amp;rsquo;Keefe and to spectacular views that were the subject of many of her pieces. For ten dollars we were granted the ability to walk the ranch and explore its popular trails. We chose to go see Chimney Rock first, as it was a moderately difficult trail that was said to be quite popular. Five minutes after starting down the trail, I turned back to awe-inspiring views of a ridge across the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-5-32.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Starting on the trail&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We exchanged pictures for a passing group of Santa Fe natives and their visiting friend before continuing up the trail. Today was one of the most beautiful days we&amp;rsquo;d experienced in New Mexico - the weather was perfect. Not to mention the ambiance - the higher we ascended, the quieter it got. We just heard the occasional whistle of the wind, and nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-5-18.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Views of Chimney Rock&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Chimney Rock come into view from the start of the trail, but there was soon a turn-out to get a better view of it. Photo cred to my mom with my camera.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was hard to capture the depth and scale of the rock from most of the vantage points - it is quite large. When we made it to the top, it was just about a rock&amp;rsquo;s throw away:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-5-05.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Starting on the trail&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before that point, we had to climb up and up and up from 6,500ft at the valley floor to 7,100ft on top of the ridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-5-10.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Trailing&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, for ten bucks the views were unbeatable. We saw a total of maybe 8 people on the trail and the diverse history of the land is super interesting. For anyone in the area, I would highly recommend coming to check out the Ghost Ranch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dinner was special tonight - Happy (early) Birthday mom! We had a tapas dinner at La Boca, and while the food was nearly fantastic, I do not recommend anyone go for reasons I outline in my OpenTable review. In essence, their service was unacceptable given the price range in spite of the delicious food which sort of ruined the whole experience in my opinion. Oh well!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Always Take the High Road</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/newmexico-2021/newmexico2021-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 08:26:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/newmexico-2021/newmexico2021-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/highroadtaos.png&#34;
        alt=&#34;High Road Map&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;em&gt;Our pre-mapped route to Taos via the iconic &amp;ldquo;high road.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After numerous recommendations from random folks on the internet, we decided that visiting Taos on the High Road was a must-do while here in New Mexico. Basically, there are two routes to Taos - one is more direct, one is more scenic but a little bit longer. You can reference the above map to get an idea for where we went and took each picture. Setting out was easy; we just followed NM84 all the way up to the highway 76 junction; as a little side note, I want to point out how slow the roads feel here in New Mexico. It seems like going over 60 miles per hour is the most dangerous thing in the world as all the highways cap at around 55. Even then, folks on the road tend to go at least 5 under. A quick search on the internet asserts that while it is true the highway speeds are slow, cops also tend to be quite lenient and speeding tickets often don&amp;rsquo;t reach beyond 20 bucks, so people who want to go fast just take the risk ~ seems a bit far fetched to me but I digress. Slowness aside, the scenes were beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first stop was the town of Chimayo. After a quick stop at the notable Chimayo weaving trading post, we set on to visit Santuario de Chimayo, a holy place with an emphasis on forgiveness and unity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-4-39.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;High Road Map&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuing on, we passed through the town of Truchas where we met a very nice lady who had some beautiful wood carvings. She told us that the most common types of carving wood in the area are aspen and cedar, being lighter and darker respectively. The carvings often incorporated both wood types, and all represented different sights, settings, people, or ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-4-29.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Wood Carving&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The dwelling of the wood carver.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon enough, after driving through a few more towns the Chimayosos mountain range came into view, and the snow-capped peaks came clear. We drove over to a turn out in the Carson National Forest to snap some pics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-4-21.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Carson 1&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we knew it, we were in Taos! Driving into town we were met with some road works, but a beautiful backdrop of the Taos ski valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-4-15.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Taos 1&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taos has all kinds of shops, boutiques, and restaurants so we took our time walking around before sitting down for some packed lunches we&amp;rsquo;d made earlier that morning. I noticed that there was a huge cell forming in the sky with rain off in the distance, so we made haste unto the Rio Grande Gorge before the heavens opened up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-4-12.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Taos 2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drive to the gorge was defined by very flat, barren lands surrounded by mountains that seemingly jut from nowhere. Until we approached the edge, you could hardly notice the gorge was even there - but of course, crossing the bridge was an entirely different story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-4-06.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Gorge&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-4-01.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Gorge 2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rain came and home we went. It was time to have a nod in the car and a good rest after our long adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tune-Up Café</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/newmexico-2021/newmexico2021-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 21:17:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/newmexico-2021/newmexico2021-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Food is this magical, diverse necessity that will - for the rest of my life - never cease to bring me joy. Each dish can have infinite variations, infinite possibilities for new flavor pairs and ideas. Often times food is an expression of something else; a deeper (or more shallow) meaning behind each dish brings with it fresh taste and renewed soul. Maybe we sit down to eat some pancakes at the local breakfast favorite; these moist disks of syrup-sponge are now the foundation upon which you will build your day, or perhaps even your entire weekend. The butter-ball slowly melts as you ready the Canadian maple syrup, and as you drizzle that liquid gold evenly across the fluffy disks and sliced strawberries, you think to yourself how lucky you are to be sitting here today, eating with your friends and family a humble breakfast, ready to take the world by storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food has the potential to be transformative, given the right context, the right cook, and the right technique. This is a form of artistic expression that everyone can enjoy, no matter where one might hail from. That being said, forms of expression show themselves in different ways; sometimes that means an explicitly bold dinner at a fine-dining restaurant - a place where the chef builds an experience around carefully crafted dishes, ambiance, and service, maintaining a high level of rigor in each pillar of expression. Other times, that expression is more humble, but delicious all the same. Such a place might be a quick local joint with specific dishes they are known for, with a more robust, upbeat atmosphere. This is the kind of place that can warm your soul, and bring you down to Earth. A kind of place where everyone feels connected in a human kind of way. Stepping into Tune-Up Cafe was transformative for these reasons and many more, and I do hope that anyone reading this who gets a chance to eat there if they find themselves in Santa Fe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and they were awesome enough to give me their recipe for tres leches cake to try myself. How awesome is that?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bandelier National Monument</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/newmexico-2021/newmexico2021-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 09:00:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/newmexico-2021/newmexico2021-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-56.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Road&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Pictured from our drive to Bandelier. It was a 45 minute drive northwest of Santa Fe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Off we go&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was a planned hiking day at one of the highly recommended spots near Santa Fe called the Bandelier National Monument. We entered the canyon at around 12:30 in the afternoon, with beautiful rock formations to the right of the road beyond the trees. After parking, mom stopped by the gift shop in search of a hat which luckily we found right away. There was a masked park ranger at a table near the gift shop entrance who pointed us in the direction of the main loop trail, and we were promptly off on our little adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-45.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Cliff Dwellings from Ground&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;View of the cliff dwellings from the ground at the bottom of the canyon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The winding, paved trailed passed grids of stone-and-mortar ruins on the valley floor before we gained a bit of altitude heading into the cliff dwellings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-40.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Cliffs&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Approaching the cliffs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we began the ascent and got closer to the cliff walls, we could see more clearly the interesting erosion of the &lt;em&gt;tuff&lt;/em&gt;, which is a type of volcanic rock that populates the walls of the valley. The rock type that make up Bandelier include tuff, obsidian, pumice, and basalt for the most part. Pictured below is a close up view of the cliff walls; you can clearly see the porous rock and unique shapes that would make it easy to expand into a dwelling space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-31.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Looking back&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Turning back to look out into the valley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, the sky was starting to transition from overcast to darker and more menacing. No matter, as we continued on through the different cliff dwelling and eventually back down to the valley floor:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-28.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Scary Sky&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there on, I was drawn to another trailhead that apparently led up to the top of the ridge - about a 1.6 mile climb in total. My mom braved the ascent until it, inevitably, began to rain. I pressed on to see the top of the ridge as she took temporary cover under a rock. I tried to be quick, as the storm was clearly developing quickly and we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be caught in it. For my efforts, I was presented with a gorgeous view of the surrounding mountains, so I quickly snapped some pics and began my descent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-15.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Ridge view&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The views were incredible, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have long before I needed to return as mom was waiting for me. Spending even just a few hours outside here in New Mexico is enough to understand the natural drama that forms the basis for so many New Mexican artist&amp;rsquo;s inspiration. The cloud formations, mountain ranges, and endless landscapes seem to not-so-subtly assert their dominance over you; all you can do is gaze in awe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found mom where we departed, and down the cliffs we went. Of course, my desire to reach the top of the ridge view trail did not come without its consequences. The heavens opened and the aforeseen storm clouds promptly dumped rain and even very small hail on us; mom decided to make a run for the home base and I walked my way there in the wet. Not wanting to give up on the day just yet, we decided to rendezvous at the little café towards the entrance and wait for the heavy rain to pass, and then we could take another trail out. About 45 minutes later after talking to the park ranger, we were directed towards the falls trail which was an easier out-and-back trail to see a small waterfall that eventually feeds into the Rio Grande.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-12.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Cool tree&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;There were lots of cool trees like this one just off the path&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-09.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Trees&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-04.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Burnt&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Fires are somewhat common here (big ones every 5 years), and there was plenty of evidence of that if you kept you eyes peeled.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-01.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Waterfall!&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;And we made it to the waterfall!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dinner was from an African-fusion joint called Jambo Cafe; I got a goat stew and mom got chicken peanut curry; both very good, and the roti on the side was delicious. Our impression was that it would have been even better if we could have eaten in the restaurant but still was great nonetheless. Tomorrow we are going to check out the Santa Fe farmer&amp;rsquo;s market and dinner will be homemade.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Been A While, Airport</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/newmexico-2021/newmexico2021-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 19:12:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/newmexico-2021/newmexico2021-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Plane #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only new thing about the airport is that KCI is getting a new terminal, but we were not in that terminal (it is only halfway done) so we just saw it from the outside. The last flight I had been on was about a year and a half ago in December of 2019, but the experience has not changed much except for that masks are a distinct requirement everywhere. My energy for the rest of the day sort of peaked right before boarding time for flight #1 to Dallas Love Field - after that I just wanted to get to our home base. I will say the flights went by fast, but having to wait in Albuquerque for our bags was rather dreadful, and it felt like each step after that took longer than the entire trip up to that point; we finally found our rental car and bid Albuquerque adeu as Santa Fe was our final destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we got to Santa Fe, we had to get the house keys from the lock-box and then find our unit (something that gave us more trouble than it should have). In the dark, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t really associate the location on Google Maps with where we were supposed to turn into, but on the second time around the block we found it and could oficially say we had arrived! Bags were unloaded, house was presented beautifully and is going to be perfect for our stay, and we were swiftly off to bed as it was nearing 1:30 Kansas-time and both mom and I were pooped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Next Morning&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only got about 7 hours of sleep last night however I feel wide awake and ready to start this adventure! I think our first order of business today is going to be to acquire some basic food items to make ourselves breakfast, etc. We plan on going to the farmer&amp;rsquo;s market in a couple of days, and I will most likely make dinner on that day as well. After scouting out some grocery stores, Trader Joes is probably where we will end up going to, but we will see - my hope was there would be something in direct walking distance and I could go acquire food before mom woke up, but in retrospect it makes the most sense for us to go together in case there is something she needed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t consider. Given the rather exhausting day prior, I think we plan on scouting out the area and doing some more granular planning for the days to come, but I will add another update towards the end of the day with details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day One Complete!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the day by storm! After a leasurely breakfast, we stopped by the local Kroger derivative (Smith&amp;rsquo;s) to get some basics for the week and then decided to walk the plaza for a lay of the land. One of the first galleries we walked by (of many, many more) had a cool dragon on the roof pictured below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-1-02.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;BW Gallery Dragon&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meandering through the streets, my mom and I were met with a series of public sculptures, all of which had differing representations, meanings, and histories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-1-11.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Sculpture 1&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, given the daylight that we didn&amp;rsquo;t have when we landed, the incredible views surrounding Santa Fe came to light. Being able to look out and see some varried elevation is always exciting for Kansans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-1-14.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Mountains!&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stucco-centric buildings and the distinct archetecture in general never really gets old. I was impressed with how clean everything is and generally how beautiful so many of the homes and buildings are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-1-17.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Nice Building&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, right outside of our rental is this beautiful church that was having service this morning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-1-18.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Church&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that wraps up day one of Santa Fe - tomorrow is a day of hiking at the Bandelier National Monument. Use the link below to check out the rest of my pictures from today&amp;rsquo;s journey:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link isn&amp;rsquo;t active yet :(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granada, España - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 17:02:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a long day the night before, my mom and I weren’t particularly quick to get out of bed. We dragged ourselves downstairs by 10:30am before the breakfast closed at 11. The breakfast was what you would expect from a standard European hotel - lots of cheeses and cold meats, alongside juice and pastries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had originally planned for this day to be a quiet day to familiarize ourself with the city, and that is almost exactly what it ended up being. After talking with the concierge, the decision was made that we would scratch our planned hike for tomorrow seen as it would be awfully expensive to get transportation there and back (roughly 100 Euros). Instead, my mom found this highly-rated night walking tour of Granada through the company Six Thrills. All I will say for now is that we were incredibly pleased with the tour, and you should definitely utilize their services if you are in the area :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We left the hotel and started to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-1.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Market Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the small, open shops you find in Granada have the same types of inventory as each other. Nonetheless, the tapestries are eye-catching, as my mom found just minutes into the start of our adventure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-2.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Tapestry Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you are out onto the main street, you have many options on where to go next - we chose to go left, and walk alongside El Rio de Darro, which is the river that surround the Alhambra. The walk is beautiful, with multiple quaint shops and tapas bars (of course) as you go East.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El Rio de Darro is not a big river - in fact, I think “moat” better describes it. Nonetheless, it inspires the growth of lots of greenery down this road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitting with the theme of Granada as a whole, cars and buses tend to drive down this small road forcing pedestrians to either side of the road as they pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-3.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Motorcycle Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you continue walking down this main street, it will eventually open up to a larger walking path to the right, and the road widens. Soon enough, you will catch your first glimpse of the Alhambra. It is difficult to see from such a low angle, but it is unmistakable nonetheless:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-4.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;First View of Granada&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we found the gates to the Alhambra further up the walkway, we decided to turn around and head back towards the hotel. We made a couple of stops along the way in order to look at the menus of some restaurants. There was also an adorable dog just soaking up the sun, so of course I had to go say hi:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-5.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Dog Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I did not at all expect was the beauty of simply walking through the city. You do not really find a contrast of modern/traditional style buildings - everything is just beautiful. This I believe is in part due to the UNESCO heritage protections. Much of Granada is protected for a variety of different reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually ventured towards El Centro - the center of the city. This is where you will find many department stores / modern clothing shops. Just before you get to El Centro, there is a small square with a hotel and many roads that converge onto the main street. We found a restaurant that we might try later called Wild Food - it is a Vegan restaurant, so it should be interesting. As it turns out, vegetarian food/tapas are very popular around here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-nightime-adventure-tour&#34;&gt;The Nightime Adventure Tour&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as I kinda mentioned above, we shifted our plans around and signed up for this “Night Adventure Tour,” which was described on Trip Advisor as a 3 hour walking tour of Granada at night. Sounds good. And the reviews were really good as well, so that is exciting. Before meeting for this tour, we ate dinner at a place called Carmela, near the vegan restaurant I mentioned. It was pretty good, and my mom found a new bottle of vino blanco she likes (I forget the name :o). Anyways, we met at the Sixthrills office and we were off with our tour guide Marija.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour started off on a good note for one main reason - there were only 3 other people on the tour besides us :D Yay! Marija took us up some of the winding streets of Granada towards our first viewpoint. She said that on Friday nights, it is exceedingly common for there to be hoards of hippies coming up to these viewpoints to smoke weed (despite its illegality). That said, there were only a couple of people at the first viewpoint, and they were indeed relaxing as one might say. This first viewpoint was overlooking Granada, but specifically the Alhambra in all of its glory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-6.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Granada Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued to climb up the winding streets, and were met with some cops who had busted the aforementioned hippies for smoking weed. Cool. Marija said that the police don’t often bother with marijuana possession, and that was the first time in her three years of residence where she had seen a legal altercation regarding weed. Cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I kinda talked about earlier, something so incredible about this city is the beauty of the buildings. Everywhere you looks, there is architectural eye candy. Eventually we made it up to the most popular, and most touristy, Alhambra viewpoint. I got my photo, and got out of there quick:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-7.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Granada Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marija told us there would be no shortage of Alhambra views, and she was definitely right. Moving on, we continued to venture up towards Sacromonte, which is the region of Granada home to the Gypsies. During this leg of the journey, we passed by many houses known as las carmenas. Each house called “carmen” was built to be self sustaining, with a large walled garden, grape vines growing on top, etc. They were absolutely beautiful. We stopped at a very quiet and peaceful bar for more views of the Alhambra as the sun set:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-8.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Granada Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-9.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Granada Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we made our way up to the tallest point in Granada, which is a church at the top of the hill, and I was able to get some final pics before we head back home for the night:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-10.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Granada Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, that was day one - it was incredible :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landed in Spain</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 17:18:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next step in our European adventure takes place in the lovely city of Granada, Spain. Our flight from Manchester was only a short 2.5 hours, and customs in Granada was a breeze (the customs agent was super cool, he gave me a stamp). Getting off the plane, we were met with the beautiful Granada sun, pictured below in all of its glory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-2-4.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Market Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our driver was prompt, and spoke little English which was to be expected. It seemed as though he and his wife were traveling together. Once we arrived at one of the principle streets in downtown Granada, we were told that we must continue our journey to the hotel on foot. We tipped the driver, and his wife accompanied us all the way to the entrance of the hotel. This is where we got our first glimpse of the labyrinth of streets that zig-zag all over Granada. As you turn the first corner, the hustle and bustle of the principle street disappears, and you are me with a much quieter, serene walk. The streets are just wide enough to fit a small car, although I would never want to be tasked with driving down them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-2-1.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Market Photo&#34;/&gt;
&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-2-2.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Market Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within minutes, we were at the hotel. We checked ourselves in, and decided that we should go out and try some of the famous tapas that we had read so much about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting back out to the main road wasn’t difficult, however deciding where to eat was. There are tapas bars everywhere. In order to give us a better idea, I tried to consult Google Maps for some of the best places to get tapas in the area. Los Diamantes was the first place on the list. We looked around, and it was right across the street from where we were standing - yay, food! But we entered the bar and there were no empty tables in sight - sad, no food. In addition to this, the overwhelming stench of seafood put my mom off, so we decided to try someplace else. Next on the list was Los Manueles. We entered, and once again were met with a lack of empty tables (you can see a theme, here…) The waitress we spoke to said 5-10 minutes for a table, but when a table finally opened up the folks behind us in line took it. I guess we needed to be more aggressive… Anyways, with each tapas bar, we slowly learned more about tapas culture, and we decided to leave once again to try one last place before giving up and calling it a night (keep in mind that at this point, it was already 11:00pm and we were tired from a day’s travel). The final tapas bar we tried was Bodegas Castaneda, about a five minute walk from Los Manueles. We finally got a table outside! Yay. A quick look over the menu prompted my mom to order a glass of Sangria and tapas frias to share. I quite enjoyed the variety of meat and cheese on toast, although my mom was not too keen (she did enjoy the pate, though). It was also relatively expensive for the amount of food you got - about 16 Euros for the medium plate. Oh well, for night one, I thought we did alright. After the bill was paid, we were off to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Few Days in the UK</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 07:13:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Arriving in the Manchester International Airport was less stressful than I initially anticipated it to be - we got through customs without even talking to anyone, got our bags within the next 10 minutes, and met up with my Aunt. In terms of sleepiness, the excitement of meeting everyone overcame that feeling for the first few hours. When we landed, mind you, it was 7:30am so I had a whole day to get through (after having got no sleep on the plane…). To help keep moving and stay awake, we took a nice walk around the block. I grabbed my camera, and we were off:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-6-1.jpg&#34;
        alt/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the tail end of our walk, we stopped at the local Latham’s for some sandwiches and sausage rolls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-6-2.jpg&#34;
        alt/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the air!</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 21:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So my really well thought out plan to beat the jet lag failed miserably. It was about 9:00pm CST, and I decided that with five hours left in the flight I should just try and go to sleep then and there, Well I got my headphones plugged in and music turned on and sleep mask ready - I was asleep in 10 minutes,,,, Only to wake up 30 minutes later, unable to sleep any longer. The universe decided that tonight was not the night for me, so here I am writing this instead,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some initial observations; I am not the only one it seems who cannot get a good night’s rest on the plane. My neighbors to the left have both surfaced and returned to their devices since I have been awake. In addition to this, the flight attendant has been by twice in the past hour to refill my hot chocolate :D I would fly Virgin Atlantic again in a heartbeat. It also helps that there are only about 15 seats occupied here on the second floor of the plane, which is a huge bonus for being able to sprawl out and (try) to sleep. From what I can tell, my mom is sleeping pretty well right now which is good because she was telling me how difficult it is for her to sleep on planes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been getting some alright videos of my journey so far, so I cant wait to take more when we land :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is it for me for tonight. Now that it is later I’m gonna try this whole sleeping thing again…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>