<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>anime on nrd blog</title>
    <link>/tags/anime/</link>
    <description>Recent content in anime on nrd blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nathanrdodson&#34;&gt;Nathan Dodson&lt;/a&gt; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/anime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fullmetal Alchemist: Brotherhood ~ 鋼の錬金術師</title>
      <link>/posts/fmab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/fmab/</guid>
      <description>Author: Nathan Dodson | Date: 05-14-2020 | Contains Spoilers
Introduction Once again, I am sitting here having just finished a show and am being inundated with all kinds of emotions. This feeling of overwhelming happiness is what I strive to find more of in life. I want to do things that makes me feel and make me reflect on my own life in positive ways. Anyway, I digress. Fullmetal Alchemist: Brotherhood was one of those unexpectedly delightful shows where I went into it having literally zero expectations - nothing more than a short synopsis from a friend - and came out of it craving more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death Note ~ デスノート</title>
      <link>/posts/deathnote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 17:32:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/deathnote/</guid>
      <description>Author: Nathan Dodson | Contains Spoilers
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure where to start here - Death Notewas a wild ride, and I am still working through my feelings about how it ended. I always develop some kind of expectation for how a show might end, and occasionally I let myself get carried away with that hyopthetical and get disappointed with how it actually ends. I can say with certainty though that Death Note ended in the only way possible - with the death of Light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Lie in April ~ 四月は君の嘘</title>
      <link>/posts/yourlieinapril/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 17:32:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/yourlieinapril/</guid>
      <description>Author: Nathan Dodson | Date: 04-07-2020 | Contains Spoilers
Introduction When I was first recomended this series, I could never have expected the level of heartache that it would incite. From the music to the character development over time, to simply the circumstance that Arima Kousei and his beloved friends are forced to endure - all of these things add up to what is a very pure account of the inner workings of a 15 year old&amp;rsquo;s mind.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>