<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TV Reviews on nrd-blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/categories/tv-reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TV Reviews on nrd-blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© Nathan Dodson 2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://blog.nathandodson.com/categories/tv-reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bandelier National Monument</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/newmexico-2021/newmexico2021-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 09:00:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/newmexico-2021/newmexico2021-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-56.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Road&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Pictured from our drive to Bandelier. It was a 45 minute drive northwest of Santa Fe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Off we go&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was a planned hiking day at one of the highly recommended spots near Santa Fe called the Bandelier National Monument. We entered the canyon at around 12:30 in the afternoon, with beautiful rock formations to the right of the road beyond the trees. After parking, mom stopped by the gift shop in search of a hat which luckily we found right away. There was a masked park ranger at a table near the gift shop entrance who pointed us in the direction of the main loop trail, and we were promptly off on our little adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-45.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Cliff Dwellings from Ground&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;View of the cliff dwellings from the ground at the bottom of the canyon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The winding, paved trailed passed grids of stone-and-mortar ruins on the valley floor before we gained a bit of altitude heading into the cliff dwellings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-40.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Cliffs&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Approaching the cliffs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we began the ascent and got closer to the cliff walls, we could see more clearly the interesting erosion of the &lt;em&gt;tuff&lt;/em&gt;, which is a type of volcanic rock that populates the walls of the valley. The rock type that make up Bandelier include tuff, obsidian, pumice, and basalt for the most part. Pictured below is a close up view of the cliff walls; you can clearly see the porous rock and unique shapes that would make it easy to expand into a dwelling space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-31.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Looking back&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Turning back to look out into the valley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, the sky was starting to transition from overcast to darker and more menacing. No matter, as we continued on through the different cliff dwelling and eventually back down to the valley floor:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-28.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Scary Sky&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there on, I was drawn to another trailhead that apparently led up to the top of the ridge - about a 1.6 mile climb in total. My mom braved the ascent until it, inevitably, began to rain. I pressed on to see the top of the ridge as she took temporary cover under a rock. I tried to be quick, as the storm was clearly developing quickly and we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be caught in it. For my efforts, I was presented with a gorgeous view of the surrounding mountains, so I quickly snapped some pics and began my descent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-15.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Ridge view&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The views were incredible, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have long before I needed to return as mom was waiting for me. Spending even just a few hours outside here in New Mexico is enough to understand the natural drama that forms the basis for so many New Mexican artist&amp;rsquo;s inspiration. The cloud formations, mountain ranges, and endless landscapes seem to not-so-subtly assert their dominance over you; all you can do is gaze in awe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found mom where we departed, and down the cliffs we went. Of course, my desire to reach the top of the ridge view trail did not come without its consequences. The heavens opened and the aforeseen storm clouds promptly dumped rain and even very small hail on us; mom decided to make a run for the home base and I walked my way there in the wet. Not wanting to give up on the day just yet, we decided to rendezvous at the little café towards the entrance and wait for the heavy rain to pass, and then we could take another trail out. About 45 minutes later after talking to the park ranger, we were directed towards the falls trail which was an easier out-and-back trail to see a small waterfall that eventually feeds into the Rio Grande.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-12.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Cool tree&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;There were lots of cool trees like this one just off the path&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-09.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Trees&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-04.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Burnt&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Fires are somewhat common here (big ones every 5 years), and there was plenty of evidence of that if you kept you eyes peeled.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-2-01.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Waterfall!&#34;/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;And we made it to the waterfall!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dinner was from an African-fusion joint called Jambo Cafe; I got a goat stew and mom got chicken peanut curry; both very good, and the roti on the side was delicious. Our impression was that it would have been even better if we could have eaten in the restaurant but still was great nonetheless. Tomorrow we are going to check out the Santa Fe farmer&amp;rsquo;s market and dinner will be homemade.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Been A While, Airport</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/newmexico-2021/newmexico2021-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 19:12:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/newmexico-2021/newmexico2021-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Plane #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only new thing about the airport is that KCI is getting a new terminal, but we were not in that terminal (it is only halfway done) so we just saw it from the outside. The last flight I had been on was about a year and a half ago in December of 2019, but the experience has not changed much except for that masks are a distinct requirement everywhere. My energy for the rest of the day sort of peaked right before boarding time for flight #1 to Dallas Love Field - after that I just wanted to get to our home base. I will say the flights went by fast, but having to wait in Albuquerque for our bags was rather dreadful, and it felt like each step after that took longer than the entire trip up to that point; we finally found our rental car and bid Albuquerque adeu as Santa Fe was our final destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we got to Santa Fe, we had to get the house keys from the lock-box and then find our unit (something that gave us more trouble than it should have). In the dark, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t really associate the location on Google Maps with where we were supposed to turn into, but on the second time around the block we found it and could oficially say we had arrived! Bags were unloaded, house was presented beautifully and is going to be perfect for our stay, and we were swiftly off to bed as it was nearing 1:30 Kansas-time and both mom and I were pooped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Next Morning&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only got about 7 hours of sleep last night however I feel wide awake and ready to start this adventure! I think our first order of business today is going to be to acquire some basic food items to make ourselves breakfast, etc. We plan on going to the farmer&amp;rsquo;s market in a couple of days, and I will most likely make dinner on that day as well. After scouting out some grocery stores, Trader Joes is probably where we will end up going to, but we will see - my hope was there would be something in direct walking distance and I could go acquire food before mom woke up, but in retrospect it makes the most sense for us to go together in case there is something she needed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t consider. Given the rather exhausting day prior, I think we plan on scouting out the area and doing some more granular planning for the days to come, but I will add another update towards the end of the day with details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day One Complete!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the day by storm! After a leasurely breakfast, we stopped by the local Kroger derivative (Smith&amp;rsquo;s) to get some basics for the week and then decided to walk the plaza for a lay of the land. One of the first galleries we walked by (of many, many more) had a cool dragon on the roof pictured below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-1-02.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;BW Gallery Dragon&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meandering through the streets, my mom and I were met with a series of public sculptures, all of which had differing representations, meanings, and histories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-1-11.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Sculpture 1&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, given the daylight that we didn&amp;rsquo;t have when we landed, the incredible views surrounding Santa Fe came to light. Being able to look out and see some varried elevation is always exciting for Kansans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-1-14.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Mountains!&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stucco-centric buildings and the distinct archetecture in general never really gets old. I was impressed with how clean everything is and generally how beautiful so many of the homes and buildings are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-1-17.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Nice Building&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, right outside of our rental is this beautiful church that was having service this morning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/newmexico2021-1-18.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Church&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that wraps up day one of Santa Fe - tomorrow is a day of hiking at the Bandelier National Monument. Use the link below to check out the rest of my pictures from today&amp;rsquo;s journey:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link isn&amp;rsquo;t active yet :(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fullmetal Alchemist: Brotherhood ~ 鋼の錬金術師</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/anime/fmab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/anime/fmab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Author: Nathan Dodson | Date: 05-14-2020 | &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contains Spoilers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, I am sitting here having just finished a show and am being inundated with all kinds of emotions. This feeling of overwhelming happiness is what I strive to find more of in life. I want to do things that makes me feel and make me reflect on my own life in positive ways. Anyway, I digress. Fullmetal Alchemist: Brotherhood was one of those unexpectedly delightful shows where I went into it having literally zero expectations - nothing more than a short synopsis from a friend - and came out of it craving more. I wanted more of Edward&amp;rsquo;s aggressive optimism, more of Winry&amp;rsquo;s compassion, more of Colonel Mustang&amp;rsquo;s grit, and more of Al&amp;rsquo;s love and consideration - I just wanted more of the show. The story told by all of these characters is one of poetic simplicity. Yes, there are some twists and turns, but the story runs simple and headstrong to its ending while living in the shadow of &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; overarching themes. There is something for literally everyone in Fullmetal Alchemist, and I am gonna touch on a few of those things that are most important to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the very beginning of the show, I will say that I was worried about the life cycle of the many different characters of whom were being introduced. Obviously, Ed and his brother are our protagonists so there was no worry there, but I was interested to see if those other characters we met along the way would remain relevant to the story and not drift into the abyss of negligibility. Well lucky for us, Fullmetal Alchemist was masterfully written, and it becomes quickly apparent that that would never be the case. Take Scar for example, whose arc is one of my favorites in the whole show. He begins as a vengeful and brutally faithful Ishvalen who was literally murdering state alchemists because of the destruction brought upon his home and to its people. By the end of the show, as we all know, Scar was an indispensable contributor to the downfall of Father and, we can assume, the rebirth of a meaningful sociopolitical relationship between Ishval and Amestris. And this is just one of many positive examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Character development also relies heavily on relationships between characters as building relationships can often be a source of perspective for individuals. Just like you might find it difficult to recognize flaws in your own character all by yourself, characters in Fullmetal Alchemist (and in most shows for that matter) are written to reflect that same disability. This fact of humanity is particularly important in FMA, emphatically reiterated through many of the complex relationships we get to see develop. Take our protagonists Edward and Alphonse Elric. These brothers are each other&amp;rsquo;s perfect compliment. Edward is often blinded by his stubbornness and persistence, a characteristic which is beneficial in its own right, however, it requires that Alphonse be there in order to prevent some of the, say, &lt;em&gt;petty&lt;/em&gt; conflict which Ed tends to attract. Edward is a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; smart kid, but he is not quite as good as Alphonse at dealing with people. He is a hot head. But it is that same undying persistence which ultimately led to the survival of Amestris - alas, it is a defining and indubitably &lt;em&gt;necessary&lt;/em&gt; trait of his. On the other side, Alphonse is a compassionate, loving, caring soul who seeks nothing more than to keep his friends safe, make people happy, and stand by his brother&amp;rsquo;s side as they journey across the country. Al is also incredibly smart and in many ways he is more powerful than Edward. Just think that he eventually succeeded in using alchemy without a transmutation circle just like Ed, and let&amp;rsquo;s not forget that he is the &lt;em&gt;younger&lt;/em&gt; brother. On top of that, his ability to connect with people, love unconditionally, forgive, protect, and support that which he loves make him the more powerful of the two. But to circle back, as I said before, neither of them could be successful all on their own. Ed and Al are also so important as a duo because they thematically represent youth. Children are naïve. They lack worldly experience, intellect, and deep emotional capacity. In these ways, Ed and Al are different than most - I think it is safe to say they have experienced a fair share of hardships in their lifetime. Some of the adults they meet along their journey are quick to call both of them naïvely optimistic, and as adults often do, dismiss them for that naïvete. But the adults that stick around the brothers eventually find solace in their optimism. They are willing to do anything to achieve the goal they set out for, and for people like Riza, Mrs. Hughes, Armstrong, and even Winry, that persistence is nothing short of inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-motif-of-fatherhood&#34;&gt;The Motif of Fatherhood&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fatherhood in FMA is nothing short of a primary focus and it is intertwined into nearly every aspect of the  .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ideas&#34;&gt;Ideas&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discuss the primary differences between the time period FMA is set in, the beauty of Amestris, how this all ties into the notion of a peaceful, post-Father society. Also talk about the warm feeling of &amp;ldquo;happily ever after&amp;rdquo; and how FMA plays so beautifully to those feels by the end of the show - relationships, how they were built over the time of the show, Ed and Al&amp;rsquo;s growth away from the structure of Alchemy, and why Winry and Ed are going to make such a fantastic, everlasting couple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/edel.bmp&#34;
        alt=&#34;Edward Elric&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.deviantart.com/oguzbuberci/art/Edward-Elric-Render-751607713&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Edward Elric by OguzBuberci on DeviantArt&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death Note ~ デスノート</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/anime/deathnote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 17:32:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/anime/deathnote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Author: Nathan Dodson | &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contains Spoilers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure where to start here - &lt;i&gt;Death Note&lt;/i&gt; was a wild ride, and I am still working through my feelings about how it ended. I always develop some kind of expectation for how a show might end, and occasionally I let myself get carried away with that hyopthetical and get disappointed with how it actually ends. I can say with certainty though that Death Note ended in the only way possible - with the death of Light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/deathnote-1.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;L&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Lie in April - 四月は君の嘘</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/anime/yourlieinapril/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 17:32:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/anime/yourlieinapril/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was first recomended this series, I could never have expected the level of heartache that it would incite. From the music to the character development over time, to simply the circumstance that Arima Kousei and his beloved friends are forced to endure - all of these things add up to what is a very pure account of the inner workings of a 15 year old&amp;rsquo;s mind. A 15 year old who had been subject to more emotional trauma than many people will experience in their entire lives. I battled with this notion in my head during the first several episodes, that we are watching &lt;em&gt;middle schoolers&lt;/em&gt; live their lives. Not high schoolers or college students, but middle schoolers. I can hardly relate to my middle school self any more as it is, so it just took some time for me to understand the intent behind that decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conclusion I ultimately came to was that I was not giving middle schoolers enough credit with regards to their capacity to love, feel deep emotions, and establish meaningful connections with other human beings. If anything, being at that age is the first time when you truly begin the battle with your inner demons. Physically changing, we begin to feel all kinds of new emotions, but that is not to disregard those emotions as fake or not genuine simply because of the correlation to a changing body and mind. I think it is super important to understand all of this when watching this show, because it can be very easy to misjudge the weight of something like Arima and Kaori&amp;rsquo;s love and their relationship overall. I think this is a good segway to begin discussing how I feel about Arima and some of the other main characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;kousei-arima&#34;&gt;Kousei Arima&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arima is a super lovable character. Simple as that. Throughout (almost) the entire show, there was hardly a time where I felt like Arima wasn&amp;rsquo;t genuine and caring to all of his friends. He consistently connects with the audience in a way that lets you understand what he is feeling, and that lends itself to an interesting dynamic where the watcher is given a peek inside Arima&amp;rsquo;s soul. His cirumstance is exceedingly unique, and I think it is safe to say that many people would not ever truly understand that which he is going through. However Arima&amp;rsquo;s character is written such that we all can find a connection to him. He represents isolation, pain, brilliance, kindness, empathy, and so much more. And it is because of all that he represents which makes him so unique as a character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kousei, for better and for worse, can attribute a lot of his underlying characteristics to his mother. Now, Saki Arima is a character who I hated from a basic human-decency perspective 98% of the time, and who I empathized with for 2% of the time, and that is being exceedingly generous. No one should ever have to endure a prolonged sickness of which ends is death. &lt;i&gt;However&lt;/i&gt;, that in absolutely no way excuses her of the years of emotional and physical trauma she caused her son. At all. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely clear to me if the physical abuse began as her disease progressed, or if it was something that Kousei always had to endure. I am thinking that it was the former due to the way Seto reacted to her hitting Kousei in the concert hall. Even so, the time when his mother was sick seemed to overlap considerably the time in which Kousei remebered her best by. Rather, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if she was different before her diagnosis because all Kousei can remember is the abuse. Unpacking Kousei and his mother&amp;rsquo;s relationship is interesting in and of itself because it really allows a deep dive into the way music defined each of them. Saki was clearly a masterful pianist, as she &amp;ldquo;coached&amp;rdquo; Kousei into being one of the most pronounced child pianists in Eastern Japan. It seems clear to me that her love and passion for music was shrouded by a growing desire to make sure Kousei had a promising and successful future to live comfortably after her death. She required nothing short of perfection from Kousei, and as a result he mastered the &lt;i&gt;utility&lt;/i&gt; of the piano. To him it was an instrument to garner his mother&amp;rsquo;s approval. It was his only tool to make her happy. But in the thick of it all, he lost the &lt;i&gt;emotion&lt;/i&gt; of the piano, as the show goes on to unfold. This is where that whole 2% thing comes in. Saki, albiet very, very poorly, was trying to make sure that her son was going to be able to survive after her passing. And I think for that she deserves an ounce of forgiveness for her treatment of Kousei. But damn did she do a piss poor job of getting that intent across to him. Kousei lost his sound shortly after his mother&amp;rsquo;s passing, which of course made all of that suffering for nothing (disregarding our beloved Kaori and her magical influence on Kousei). She tried so hard to help him, that in the end Saki ended up even farther from her son than where she started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that brings us front and center to the Kousei we know from the beginning of the show. The broken Kousei. Pre-Kaori Kousei, if you will. I would characterize Kousei at the beginning of the show as lost, to put it lightly. Stuck in front of the piano at school, he lies there having just been hit in the head by Tsubaki&amp;rsquo;s softball. The pilot episode is a light-hearted establishment of the types of characters we are dealing with. From the beginning, we already see that there are contrasting elements to Tsubaki and Kousei&amp;rsquo;s character. As the show progresses we learn that those elements are why they make such good friends, but also why Tsubaki and Kousei could never be anything more than friends. That is even independent of the fact that Kousei is so clearly in love with Kaori. I was overly critical of Kousei and Tsubaki&amp;rsquo;s relationship development at first, seen as it was so obvious that it would never materialize into anything meaningful. I initially thought it was wasteful and lazy writing to put Tsubaki in that position, hooked on this idea that a deep, mutually-platonic friendship could mean so much more for the show. But as you often need to do when watching &lt;i&gt;Your Lie in April&lt;/i&gt; I reflected on a core aspect of the show - these kids are all middle schoolers. And that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean we have to lower our expectations of their capacity to feel deep emotion, love, and care for one another. But it does me we have to alter those expectations to fit the mold of, well, a middle schooler. And when we do that, it becomes clear that Tsubaki&amp;rsquo;s actions fit that mold clearly. She loves Kousei with all her heart, and she can&amp;rsquo;t help how she feels towards Kousei, and she has every right to be upset about the circumstance. But the reality is Kousei loves someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/yourlieinapril1.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Kousei Piano&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granada, España - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 17:02:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a long day the night before, my mom and I weren’t particularly quick to get out of bed. We dragged ourselves downstairs by 10:30am before the breakfast closed at 11. The breakfast was what you would expect from a standard European hotel - lots of cheeses and cold meats, alongside juice and pastries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had originally planned for this day to be a quiet day to familiarize ourself with the city, and that is almost exactly what it ended up being. After talking with the concierge, the decision was made that we would scratch our planned hike for tomorrow seen as it would be awfully expensive to get transportation there and back (roughly 100 Euros). Instead, my mom found this highly-rated night walking tour of Granada through the company Six Thrills. All I will say for now is that we were incredibly pleased with the tour, and you should definitely utilize their services if you are in the area :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We left the hotel and started to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-1.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Market Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the small, open shops you find in Granada have the same types of inventory as each other. Nonetheless, the tapestries are eye-catching, as my mom found just minutes into the start of our adventure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-2.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Tapestry Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you are out onto the main street, you have many options on where to go next - we chose to go left, and walk alongside El Rio de Darro, which is the river that surround the Alhambra. The walk is beautiful, with multiple quaint shops and tapas bars (of course) as you go East.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El Rio de Darro is not a big river - in fact, I think “moat” better describes it. Nonetheless, it inspires the growth of lots of greenery down this road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitting with the theme of Granada as a whole, cars and buses tend to drive down this small road forcing pedestrians to either side of the road as they pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-3.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Motorcycle Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you continue walking down this main street, it will eventually open up to a larger walking path to the right, and the road widens. Soon enough, you will catch your first glimpse of the Alhambra. It is difficult to see from such a low angle, but it is unmistakable nonetheless:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-4.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;First View of Granada&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we found the gates to the Alhambra further up the walkway, we decided to turn around and head back towards the hotel. We made a couple of stops along the way in order to look at the menus of some restaurants. There was also an adorable dog just soaking up the sun, so of course I had to go say hi:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-5.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Dog Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I did not at all expect was the beauty of simply walking through the city. You do not really find a contrast of modern/traditional style buildings - everything is just beautiful. This I believe is in part due to the UNESCO heritage protections. Much of Granada is protected for a variety of different reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually ventured towards El Centro - the center of the city. This is where you will find many department stores / modern clothing shops. Just before you get to El Centro, there is a small square with a hotel and many roads that converge onto the main street. We found a restaurant that we might try later called Wild Food - it is a Vegan restaurant, so it should be interesting. As it turns out, vegetarian food/tapas are very popular around here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-nightime-adventure-tour&#34;&gt;The Nightime Adventure Tour&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as I kinda mentioned above, we shifted our plans around and signed up for this “Night Adventure Tour,” which was described on Trip Advisor as a 3 hour walking tour of Granada at night. Sounds good. And the reviews were really good as well, so that is exciting. Before meeting for this tour, we ate dinner at a place called Carmela, near the vegan restaurant I mentioned. It was pretty good, and my mom found a new bottle of vino blanco she likes (I forget the name :o). Anyways, we met at the Sixthrills office and we were off with our tour guide Marija.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour started off on a good note for one main reason - there were only 3 other people on the tour besides us :D Yay! Marija took us up some of the winding streets of Granada towards our first viewpoint. She said that on Friday nights, it is exceedingly common for there to be hoards of hippies coming up to these viewpoints to smoke weed (despite its illegality). That said, there were only a couple of people at the first viewpoint, and they were indeed relaxing as one might say. This first viewpoint was overlooking Granada, but specifically the Alhambra in all of its glory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-6.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Granada Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued to climb up the winding streets, and were met with some cops who had busted the aforementioned hippies for smoking weed. Cool. Marija said that the police don’t often bother with marijuana possession, and that was the first time in her three years of residence where she had seen a legal altercation regarding weed. Cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I kinda talked about earlier, something so incredible about this city is the beauty of the buildings. Everywhere you looks, there is architectural eye candy. Eventually we made it up to the most popular, and most touristy, Alhambra viewpoint. I got my photo, and got out of there quick:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-7.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Granada Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marija told us there would be no shortage of Alhambra views, and she was definitely right. Moving on, we continued to venture up towards Sacromonte, which is the region of Granada home to the Gypsies. During this leg of the journey, we passed by many houses known as las carmenas. Each house called “carmen” was built to be self sustaining, with a large walled garden, grape vines growing on top, etc. They were absolutely beautiful. We stopped at a very quiet and peaceful bar for more views of the Alhambra as the sun set:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-8.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Granada Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-9.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Granada Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we made our way up to the tallest point in Granada, which is a church at the top of the hill, and I was able to get some final pics before we head back home for the night:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-3-10.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Granada Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, that was day one - it was incredible :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landed in Spain</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 17:18:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next step in our European adventure takes place in the lovely city of Granada, Spain. Our flight from Manchester was only a short 2.5 hours, and customs in Granada was a breeze (the customs agent was super cool, he gave me a stamp). Getting off the plane, we were met with the beautiful Granada sun, pictured below in all of its glory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-2-4.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Market Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our driver was prompt, and spoke little English which was to be expected. It seemed as though he and his wife were traveling together. Once we arrived at one of the principle streets in downtown Granada, we were told that we must continue our journey to the hotel on foot. We tipped the driver, and his wife accompanied us all the way to the entrance of the hotel. This is where we got our first glimpse of the labyrinth of streets that zig-zag all over Granada. As you turn the first corner, the hustle and bustle of the principle street disappears, and you are me with a much quieter, serene walk. The streets are just wide enough to fit a small car, although I would never want to be tasked with driving down them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-2-1.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Market Photo&#34;/&gt;
&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-2-2.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Market Photo&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within minutes, we were at the hotel. We checked ourselves in, and decided that we should go out and try some of the famous tapas that we had read so much about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting back out to the main road wasn’t difficult, however deciding where to eat was. There are tapas bars everywhere. In order to give us a better idea, I tried to consult Google Maps for some of the best places to get tapas in the area. Los Diamantes was the first place on the list. We looked around, and it was right across the street from where we were standing - yay, food! But we entered the bar and there were no empty tables in sight - sad, no food. In addition to this, the overwhelming stench of seafood put my mom off, so we decided to try someplace else. Next on the list was Los Manueles. We entered, and once again were met with a lack of empty tables (you can see a theme, here…) The waitress we spoke to said 5-10 minutes for a table, but when a table finally opened up the folks behind us in line took it. I guess we needed to be more aggressive… Anyways, with each tapas bar, we slowly learned more about tapas culture, and we decided to leave once again to try one last place before giving up and calling it a night (keep in mind that at this point, it was already 11:00pm and we were tired from a day’s travel). The final tapas bar we tried was Bodegas Castaneda, about a five minute walk from Los Manueles. We finally got a table outside! Yay. A quick look over the menu prompted my mom to order a glass of Sangria and tapas frias to share. I quite enjoyed the variety of meat and cheese on toast, although my mom was not too keen (she did enjoy the pate, though). It was also relatively expensive for the amount of food you got - about 16 Euros for the medium plate. Oh well, for night one, I thought we did alright. After the bill was paid, we were off to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Few Days in the UK</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 07:13:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Arriving in the Manchester International Airport was less stressful than I initially anticipated it to be - we got through customs without even talking to anyone, got our bags within the next 10 minutes, and met up with my Aunt. In terms of sleepiness, the excitement of meeting everyone overcame that feeling for the first few hours. When we landed, mind you, it was 7:30am so I had a whole day to get through (after having got no sleep on the plane…). To help keep moving and stay awake, we took a nice walk around the block. I grabbed my camera, and we were off:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-6-1.jpg&#34;
        alt/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the tail end of our walk, we stopped at the local Latham’s for some sandwiches and sausage rolls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img  src=&#34;https://blog.nathandodson.com/img/europe2019-6-2.jpg&#34;
        alt/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the air!</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 21:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So my really well thought out plan to beat the jet lag failed miserably. It was about 9:00pm CST, and I decided that with five hours left in the flight I should just try and go to sleep then and there, Well I got my headphones plugged in and music turned on and sleep mask ready - I was asleep in 10 minutes,,,, Only to wake up 30 minutes later, unable to sleep any longer. The universe decided that tonight was not the night for me, so here I am writing this instead,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some initial observations; I am not the only one it seems who cannot get a good night’s rest on the plane. My neighbors to the left have both surfaced and returned to their devices since I have been awake. In addition to this, the flight attendant has been by twice in the past hour to refill my hot chocolate :D I would fly Virgin Atlantic again in a heartbeat. It also helps that there are only about 15 seats occupied here on the second floor of the plane, which is a huge bonus for being able to sprawl out and (try) to sleep. From what I can tell, my mom is sleeping pretty well right now which is good because she was telling me how difficult it is for her to sleep on planes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been getting some alright videos of my journey so far, so I cant wait to take more when we land :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is it for me for tonight. Now that it is later I’m gonna try this whole sleeping thing again…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip Preparation</title>
      <link>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 11:32:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.nathandodson.com/posts/europe-2019/europe2019-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my trip to Europe, my preparation has been significantly more intensive than what would be considered “normal” on previous trips I’ve had. This is mainly because I have set a few goals for myself, some small, and some much larger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For starters, I want to beat the jet lag - at least on my flight to Manchester. Our current itinerary has us leaving Atlanta at 6:00PM and arriving in Manchester just before 7:00AM. This means that I will need to sleep the entire flight to have energy for the day in Manchester. In order to achieve this, I have started to do a few things: one, I went to bed at around 9:00PM Monday night and woke up at around 3:00AM the next morning (the morning I am writing this :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to repeat this same sleep routine tonight, and maybe even go to bed a little earlier. The goal here is to be tired an hour or two into the flight so I can sleep the rest of the way. I will then, assuming all goes as planned, continue to ease back into my normal sleep routine on GMT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next goal of mine is to take more video, and this means two separate things. I want to not only work on my video skills as a photographer, but in the spirit of documenting more, I want to get more video of everyday things happening, and me doing things as simple as spending time with my family. I am not sure about doing “vlog” style videos, as I am not particularly comfortable in front of the camera, however I will certainly be using my GoPro for significant amounts of footage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I want to continue to stay healthy on this trip, and get back into my workouts. This should be pretty easy to do, knock on wood…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So those are my goals, but how else am I prepping for this trip?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, in the spirit of documenting things, I wanted to have access to mobile data while on this trip. I did some research, and Google’s Project Fi was the perfect option. The price breakdown is pretty straightforward. $20 for unlimited texting internationally (with varying rate of calls outside of North America), and $10 dollars for every gig of data up to 6 gigs. After the 6th gig, you get unlimited data, but it is throttled to a whopping 256k… If you want, you can enable speedy data again with the same price per gig coming back as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, I also needed to pack all of my SD cards. These are all of them, plus a 128GB card currently in my camera, and another 32GB card in my GoPro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, that is all for now :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>